# Alex Kenny

# **Full-stack**

# **Software**

# Developer

Dublin, Ireland +353 85 712 6444 alexkenny1@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

I'm currently transitioning into tech. through software development and recently completed a full-stack coding course, achieving first class honours.

I'm trained specifically in current front-end and back-end technologies.

I also hold a masters in applied digital media and a diploma in project management.

My background is in digital communications in the position of client manager. I also have experience in digital project management and web development.

I'm interested in finding a role that is a good fit for me and allows me to continue to use and learn code.

I have created a portfolio site to demonstrate my skills in web and software development and to showcase my recent projects.

Portfolio / al3xk3nny.github.io/portfolio/

#### **Skills**

# **Technical Skills**

Wireframe / Balsamiq

Languages / HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python

Frameworks / Flask | Django

Databases / MySQL (PostgresQL) | NoSQL (MongoDB)

Cloud Platforms / Heroku | AWS

#### Soft Skills

- ★ Creative and innovative thinker
- ★ Analytical thinking and decision making
- **★** Teamwork
- ★ Planning and organising

# **Education**

#### Code Institute / Diploma in Software Development

2018 - 2018, DUBLIN

First Class Honors

#### Griffith College Dublin / Master of Science in Applied Digital Media

2012 - 2014, DUBLIN

First Class Honors

# **Dublin Business School** / Diploma in Project Management

2009 - 2009, DUBLIN

Distinction

# Fitzwilliam Institute / Diploma in Advertising

2004 - 2005, DUBLIN

Credit

# University College Dublin / Bachelor of Arts

2000 - 2003, DUBLIN

Second Class Honors, Grade Two

# **Experience**

#### **DDFH&B** / Account Director

FEBRUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2018, DUBLIN

Advertising and marketing

Managed a team to deliver successful campaigns on behalf of top performing companies in the insurance, automotive and merchant service industries.

- ★ Played a key role in convincing the Liberty Insurance client to pursue a strategy to prepare young drivers for the *Real Road*. This ultimately became the proposition for 2018's successful *Ready for the Real World* campaign.
- ★ Worked with the AIB Merchant Service and AIB brand marketing teams to coordinate and upsell the merchant service offering more than doubling their market presence and position within 6 months.
- ★ Took responsibility for GDPR compliance and roll-out across the agency. My approach was ultimately used as a benchmark for other companies within the parent group.

# **WONDR** / Digital Producer

AUGUST 2016 - FEBRUARY 2017, DUBLIN

Digital strategy and marketing

Worked collaboratively with WONDR digital architects in the definition and delivery of client's key strategic projects.

- ★ Project managed the successful launch of Cliff Group suite of websites.
- ★ Provided strategy and delivery for *Healthy Recipes* and the divisive *Stop Targeting Kids* campaigns for Irish Heart.
- ★ Successful in delivering the Irish Heart website migration project on time and on budget through an agile approach to creative design, media and tech.

#### RMG / Senior Digital Account Manager

NOVEMBER 2013 - AUGUST 2016, DUBLIN

Digital and direct marketing

Project managed successful content marketing and digital campaigns on strategy and against agreed KPIs.

- ★ Worked with ATL advertising partners to maintain SuperValu's position as number 1 multiple in the Irish market for 3 successive years.
- ★ Delivered industry recognised web development projects for SuperValu including the 2013/2014 *Real Food* campaign and the 2014/2015 *Good Food Karma* campaign.
- ★ Played a part in the successful pitch for the Laya Healthcare account and managed the digital account thereon, including the first-to-market Laya *Lifetime Community Rating* (*LCR*) campaign.

# ADFORCE / Senior Agency Account Manager

JANUARY 2010 - JULY 2013, DUBLIN

Mobile advertising and marketing

Worked with sales leadership team to successfully launch Ireland's first mobile ad network whilst enabling brands in the rapidly emerging mobile internet economy.

- ★ Delivered publishing production process definition and improvement for the implementation of mobile rich media technologies.
- ★ Took responsibility to provide lectures in mobile advertising and marketing to brands and skill bodies as part of an up-sell initiative.

#### **Interests**

I am a member of a hockey club and enjoy getting involved in the organisational aspects of running a social club. I also enjoy personal technology.